A Guide to the General or Miscellaneous audiovisual materials FA466
Rockefeller Archive Center
General or Miscellaneous audiovisual materials
1927-2007
Rockefeller Archive Center
Eisenhower, Dwight D. (Dwight D.) (1890-1969)
FA466
1 Item(s) Actual extent unknown.
Conditions Governing Access note
Open for research. When requesting to view audiovisual material, please refer to the Title and the AV Number (example: AV 1916). Researchers are asked to check the "Restrictions" note for each Title. If a Title does not currently have an access copy, please contact a RAC archivist for further instruction.
Separated Materials note
The majority of audiovisual materials have been physically separated from an archival collection.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
In most cases, the specific details of the provenance are unknown.
Arrangement
As received.
Scope and Contents
This aggregation of miscellaneous audiovisual materials is an artificial collection created by the RAC in order to efficiently and effectively manage and present the miscellaneous moving images and audio materials held among our archival holdings.
Sound recordings; Moving Images
- General or Miscellaneous films, 1927-1965; 1
  Scope and Contents
  The original provenance, and/or specific association with RAC archival holdings, of the films presented in this series is unknown.
  Arrangement
  Alphabetical.
  Conditions Governing Access
  Open for research. When requesting to view audiovisual material, please refer to the Title and the AV Number (example: AV 1916). Researchers are asked to check the "Restrictions" note for each Title. If a Title does not currently have an access copy, please contact a RAC archivist for further instruction.
  All inquiries to view films require advanced notice of at least 2 business days, and may necessitate notice of up to one week. Individual items, including those that are not available in modern formats, may be restricted at the discretion of RAC.
  Moving Images
  - St. Mihiel Drive, 1927; United States. Army. Signal Corps; Silent, Black & white, 9 minutes. (Reel AV 2245)
    Produced by the Signal Corps of the U.S. Army taken under action and service conditions in France. Film depicts General Pershing in his office; trucks and troops move up a road; artillery is fired; patrols cut through barbered wire; infantry advance behind tranks; DH-4 airplanes lined up on an airfield; artillery is moved, loaded, and fired; the infantry crosses captured enemy trenches; refugees are fed; POWs are hered to the rear. The St. Mihiel Drive was a World War I battle fought between September 12-15, 1918.
    File Plan
    J
    World War I; Newsreels; Documentary films; France -- History; Pershing, John J. (John Joseph), 1860-1948
  - One Out of Nine, 1946; 35mm film; Sound, Black and white, 4 minutes (Reel AV 723)
    Access copy available.
    Cancer awareness film focusing on the on-going work at New York City's Memorial Cancer Center. Actor Fredric March narrates and appears in the film to urge viewers to donate to the Memorial Cancer Center Fund.
  - Victory Clothing Drive, circa 1946; Sound, Black and white, 2 minutes; 35mm film (Reel AV 1946)
    Conditions Governing Access note
    Scope and Contents note
    Short public service announcement featuring Spencer Tracy encouraging Americans to donate clothes for European war victims.
  - Henry Lends a Hand, 1952 November; Sound, Black & white, 700 ft/19 minutes. Only available on original 16mm film. (Reel AV 1699)
    short film about political volunteerism in America, made by the Committee for Political Education and Information.
    III 14.5-9
  - Legislature Grants Privilege for Community to Vote for Progress, 1953 June 3; Sound, Black & white, 200 ft./6 minutes. Only available on 16mm film. (Reel AV 1605)
    Westchester, NY towns of Tarrytown and North Tarrytown merger campaign
    III 14.9-2
  - Grand Teton National Park, 1958; Silent, Color, 10 minutes. Only available on original 16mm film. (Reel AV 1616)
    Promotional film made by Frontier Airlines with scenes of horseback riding, river rafting, Jackson Lake Lodge, artist painting in the forest.
    III 14.6-3
  - Dwight D. Eisenhower in Puerto Rico I, 1960 March 4; Some sound, Black & white and color, 10-15 minutes each. Only available on original 16mm film. (Reel AV 1615)
    President Eisenhower concludes a South America tour in Puerto Rico to address the American Assembly; luncheon, golfing at Dorado Beach Hotel.
    III 14.6-12
  - Dwight D. Eisenhower in Puerto Rico II, 1960 March 4; Some sound, Black & white and color, 10-15 minutes each. Only available on original 16mm film. (Reel AV 1104)
    III 14.6-14 OR III 14.2 FD 41
  - Dwight D. Eisenhower in Puerto Rico III, 1960 March 4; Some sound, Black & white and color, 10-15 minutes each. Only available on original 16mm film. (Reel AV 1105)
    III 14.6-13
  - Golden Opportunities: Preservation of California Beaches and Parks, 1960s; Sound, Color, 12 minutes, only available on original 16mm film. (Reel AV 1651)
    Production about the population explosion in California. Visits to Seal Rock, Monte Rey, Spanish Mission, Sutter's Fort, Hearst Castle, and Redwood Forest. Narrated and produced by Walt Disney.
    III 14.6-9
  - Eye on New York: The Forgotten River, 1965 October 31; Sound, Color, 30 minutes. Only available on original 16mm film. (Reel AV 1641)
    Episode about the Hudson River.
    III 14.1 Ff 9
  - Time to Begin, 1965; 16mm film (Reel AV 2966)
    Access copy currently unavailable. Please contact a RAC archivist for further instruction.
    short film produced by Colonial Williamsburg, Inc. for the Governor's Conference on Natural Beauty: threatened environment; potential loss of U.S. natural resources; pollution of land, water, etc.
  - The Effects of Morphine on Learned Adaptive Behavior and Experimental Neurosis in Cats, Silent, Black & white, 6 minutes. Only available on original 16mm film. (Reel AV 1266)
    Film from the Neurophysiology Laboratories and the Division of Psychiatry at the Otho S.A. Sprague Memorial Institute and the University of Chicago. Summary of experimental work by Jules H. Masserman, M.D., University of Chicago, and Adam Wikler, M.D., U.S. Public Health Service. Contains some graphic footage of experiments on cats in a laboratory setting.
  - Peace Corps 2, Sound, Color, 6 minutes. Only available on original 16mm film. (Reel AV 1115)
    A short NBC film about Peace Corp training, produced by the network
  - Vacationland USA, Only available on original 16mm film (Reel AV 1614)
    Warner Brothers tourism film showcasing Snake River, Grand Teton National Park, and includes the site of "Spencer's Mountain", a major Hollywood movie, with Arthur Godfrey, Henry Fonda, and Wally Cox.
    III 14.6-4
  - The Nobel Prize in Medicine, 1967; 16mm film on Digital Betacam; Sound, Black and white, 20 minutes (Box 1, Tape AV 11736)
    Interviews with Ragnar Granit, George Wald, Haldan Keffer Hartline.
- General or Miscellaneous audio materials
  Sound recordings
  - Social Responsiveness of Philanthropic Foundations Tape 1, 28-29 October 2007 (1/4 inch audio cassette AV 6885)
  - Social Responsiveness of Philanthropic Foundations Tape 2, 28-29 October 2007 (1/4 inch audio cassette AV 6886)
  - Social Responsiveness of Philanthropic Foundations Tape 3, 28-29 October 2007 (1/4 inch audio cassette AV 6887)
  - Social Responsiveness of Philanthropic Foundations Tape 4, 28-29 October 2007 (1/4 inch audio cassette AV 6888)
  - Social Responsiveness of Philanthropic Foundations Tape 5, 28-29 October 2007 (1/4 inch audio cassette AV 6889)
  - Social Responsiveness of Philanthropic Foundations Tape 6, 28-29 October 2007 (1/4 inch audio cassette AV 6890)
  - Social Responsiveness of Philanthropic Foundations Tape 7, 28-29 October 2007 (1/4 inch audio cassette AV 6891)
  - Social Responsiveness of Philanthropic Foundations Tape 8, 28-29 October 2007 (1/4 inch audio cassette AV 6892)